J. P. Harrington and Company Records
© 2004 University of Connecticut
J. P. Harrington and Company Records.
1860-1900.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
J. P. Harrington and Company.
2.5 linear feet.
The collection consists of the financial records of J.P. Harrington and Company, general merchants of Collinsville, Connecticut.
MSS19790007
History
The existing records of J.P. Harrington and Company, general merchants of Collinsville, Connecticut (Hartford County) span the years from 1860 to 1900. The company was founded (circa 1860) by Jarvis P. Harrington (1833-1900) and his brother, Henry E. Harrington. By 1876, the partnership had become Harrington and Hotchkiss (see entry in inventory book for 1876); and in 1878 the firm was renamed Harrington and Hart. From early 1883 to 1900, the firm seems to have been retained solely by Jarvis Harrington. It was renamed J.P. Harrington and Company in 1883. Throughout its existence, the store carried a variety of groceries, dry goods, footwear, glassware, and animal feed.
Sources:
J.P. Harrington and Company Records.
Commemorative Biographical Record of Hartford County Connecticut. Chicago: J.H. Beers & Co., 1901.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of the financial records of J.P. Harrington and Company, general merchants of Collinsville, Connecticut.
Organization
Series I: General Account and Inventory Books ( 1860-1900 ) consists of one ledger, four day books, and one inventory book. The ledger, subtitled "Bills payable and bankable savings," contains financial information concerning invoices received by J.P. Harrington and Co. from its suppliers, as well as information concerning bank deposits and available assets. The four day books provide a listing of daily transactions in the store, 1878-1880. The inventory book contains periodic accountings of the sellable property owned by the store; and provides a listing of the types of material available to J.P. Harrington and Company's customers. These record books are arranged by type, and chronologically within type where applicable.
Series II: Invoices ( 1876-1895 ) consists of invoices received by J.P. Harrington and Co. from its suppliers in Connecticut, Massachusetts, and New York, chronologically by state and city.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut business records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
Harrington and Hotchkiss (Collinsville, Conn.); Harrington and Hart (Collinsville, Conn.)
Family Names:
Harrington, Jarvis P., 1833-1900.; Harrington, Henry E.
Places:
Connecticut-Business, industries, and trades-General stores.; Massachusetts-Business, industries, and trades.; New York (State)-Business, industries, and trades.; Collinsville (Conn.)--Business, industries, and trades.
Subjects:
Subjects:
General stores-Connecticut.
Document Types:
Financial Records.; Inventories.
Occupations:
Merchants.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Yale University Library to the University of Connecticut in 1979.
Detailed Description
- Series I: General Account and Inventory Books, 1860-1900
  - Ledger: Bills payable and bankable savings, 1860-1900 (Box 1:1)
  - Day Books (3), 1878-1879 (Box 1:2)
  - Day Books, 1880 (Box 1:3)
  - Inventory Books, 1867-1871, 1876 (Box 1:4)
- Series II: Invoices, 1878-1895
  - Connecticut
    - Burlington (& Tarriffville), 1880-1885 (Box 2:5)
    - Collinsville, 1878-1885 (Box 2:6)
    - Hartford, 1878-1886 (Box 2:7-27)
    - New Hartford, 1879-1886 (Box 2:28)
    - New Haven, 1878-1886 (Box 2:29-41)
    - New London, 1884 (Box 2:42)
    - Waterbury, 1878-1886 (Box 2:43)
    - Winsted, 1882 (Box 2:44)
  - Massachusetts
    - Boston, 1878-1880 (Box 3:45-46)
    - Cambridgeport, 1879-1884 (Box 3:47)
    - Springfield, 1878-1886 (Box 3:48)
  - New York
    - Buffalo, 1882-1886 (Box 3:49)
    - New York City, 1882-1883 (Box 3:50)
  - Rhode Island
    - Providence, 1876, 1878-1881 (Box 3:51)